She was having a perfectly bad day... Then he came along and spoiled it.
One Fine Day is a romance, comedy film directed by Michael Hoffman.
Melanie Parker, an architect and mother of Sammy, and Jack Taylor, a
newspaper columnist and father of Maggie, are both divorced.
They meet one morning when overwhelmed Jack is left unexpectedly with
Maggie and forgets that Melanie was to take her to school.
As a result, both children miss their school field
trip and are stuck with the parents.
The two adults project their negative stereotypes of ex-spouses on each other, but end up
needing to rely on each other to watch the children as each must save his job.
Humor is added by Sammy's propensity for lodging objects in
his nose and Maggie's tendency to wander.
Melanie Parker, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Jack Taylor, played by George Clooney.
Maggie Taylor, Jack's daughter, played by Mae Whitman.
Sammy Parker, Melanie's son, played by Alex D. Linz.
Lew, Jack's boss, played by Charles Durning.
Mr. Yates, Jr., played by Jon Robin Baitz.
One Fine Day is a 1996 American romantic comedy-drama film directed by
Michael Hoffman, starring Michelle Pfeiffer and George Clooney.
Linz and Mae Whitman play their children.
The title comes from the 1963 song "One Fine Day" by
Carole King, which is heard in the film.
Pfeiffer served as an executive producer for the film, which was
produced in association with her company Via Rosa Productions.
The film was nominated for an Academy Award for Best
Original Song ("For the First Time").
The film explores themes of single mother, divorced,
single father, family conflict, child custody.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.